Contact details:

O Cork, Ireland

+353867918594

quinlanrobert@yahoo.com

Robert's Linkedin

Portfolio website

Robert's Github

Native Language: ISL Fluent (Irish Sign Language) | English

Skills

Language: HTML | CSS | Python | JavaScript | Markdown

Version Control: Heroku | GitHub | Gitpod

Frameworks: Flask | Django | **Bootstrap**

Libraries: jQuery

Database: ElephantSQL

API Platform: Stripe | Cloudinary

Soft Skills: Project Management | Agile GitHub | Teamwork | Time Management | Organisation

Microsoft: Word | Excel | PowerPoint | Outlook

Creative Adobe: Photoshop | Illustrator | After Effect | Premiere Pro & FCPX

Operating System: iMac | Mac ProBook | iOS | Windows 11

Digital Media: Video editing | Graphic Motion | **Photography**

Robert Quinlan

Junior Full Stack Software Developer

Summary Experience

Highly motivated Junior software developer with a Diploma in full stack software development. Experienced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. Capable across the front and backend. Complimentary BA honours degree in Multimedia, with 4+ years' experience in graphic design, photography, motion graphics and project management. Creative, logical and solutions focused approach to web development. Seeking a junior position within a diverse working environment where I can continue to build on my technical skills and contribute positively to a team.

Please note: I require an ISL interpreter for meetings. Remote role desired.

Education

Code Institute | Online | Dublin - Duration: 2022 - 2023 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development in e-learning

MTU | Cork - Duration: 2012 - 2016 Bachelor of Arts Honours - Multimedia

KDRC | Tralee, Co. Kerry - Duration: 2005 - 2006

Certification - Tutor ISL

CIT | Cork - Duration: 2005 - 2005 Certification - Web Design & Construction

CIT | Cork - Duration: 2000 - 2003

Higher Certificate - Computing Information Technology

Code Institute | Portfolios

- Michael Collins Legend, Michael Collins history and museums to visit locations - Site live Michael Collins Legend, Technology Used: HTML & CSS
- Movie Quiz, Interactive quiz the question and option answers Sites live in Movies Quiz Game, Technology Used: HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Tic Tac Toe, Interactive the Tic Tac Toe game Sites live in <u>Tic Tac Toe</u> Game, Technology Used: Python
- Order Foods & Delivery, Order foods online and delivery Sites live in Order Foods & Delivery, Technology Used: HTML, CSS, & Python
- Fine Art Gallery, the customer purchases a Fine Art Gallery online Sites live in Fine Art Gallery, Technology Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Python
- Robert Quinlan's resume site has all portfolios included above the 5 portfolio projects please find the site live in the portfolio

Experience

Career break/Parental responsibilities

Cork | Mar 2020 - Present

- During the pandemic, I had to take care of my children and support them with remote schooling full-time.
- Pursue further education by studying Full Stack Software Development with Code Institute.

Freelance - Photographic Editor & Animator

Tipperary | Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

- Assisting artistic director in editing photography & motion graphics.
- importing photos onto computer and structuring folders.
- Formatting & exporting film for Library Exhibition.

Internship - Multimedia Production

Central Statistical Office (CSO) | Cork | Sep 2017 – Jul 2018

- Project management & development of concepts for design of the animation.
- Graphic design and storyboard.
- Video editing and motion graphics.
- Sound editing (with assistance from a colleague).

Business Development Co-Ordinator

Cork Deaf Enterprise | Cork | May 2017 - Sep 2017

- Concept design accordance with accessibility needs of Deaf/Hard of Hearing staff in.
- Design and development of both software and hardware for project management.
- Delivery of the product prototype.

Entrepreneur Programme

Rubicon Centre | CIT | Cork | Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

- proposal planning, business research.
- writing business strategies for the ISL e-learning online.
- designed and developed the user interface (UI), interaction logic, and presentation of sign language.
- deliver an audience presentation that showcased of my business idea, my idea was to teach sign language e-learning online.

Store Person/Clerical Officer (Part-time)

A to Z Safety Centre | Cork | Dec 2004 - July 2012

- duties included importing the packing and putting up the boxes on the shelves.
- packing items for delivery.
- · general office work.

Tutor ISL (Irish Sign Language) – Freelancer

Varies locations | Cork | Sep 2004 - June 2012

- · Create design in ISL material for handout
- Teaching in ISL to students/adults
- Assessment of each student/adult

Artistic Director

Spirit of Sign | Cork | Sep 2006 – Sep 2012

- Theatre coordinator/producer/choreographer.
- Director, Storyboard, Make-up, Video Editing, Costume Design, Motion Graphics, Graphic Design and Filmmaker.
- · Organised fundraising.

Hobbies and Interests

- JavaScript keep learning as long I need
- Creative CSS has a monthly subscription; creating CSS with images is unique. I used <u>CODEPEN</u> to learn how to create an image using CSS
- Innovation for Accessibility Technology See my blog <u>Alert Accessibility</u>
- Photography and editing PhotoShop my portfolio select to photography
- Creative design See my portfolio in Graphic Design
- Travel & Visit Museums